Ohhh!
Meet oa and ow — two friends who both make the long O sound...
oooh!
You hear that sound in boat...
and in snow!
Same sound...
different spelling!
But how do we know which one to use?
Here's an easy way to remember!
Think of a little boat.
oa loves to sail in the middle of a word.
b-o-a-t…
boat!
Now think of a big wave.
ow loves the end of a word.
s-n-o-w...
snow!
Let's try some more words!
Coat...
goat...
toast...
oa is in the middle.
Grow...
blow...
yellow...
ow is at the end!
Now it's your turn!
Which one goes here?
road...
oa or ow?
It's oa — because it's in the middle!
oa sails in the middle, and ow rolls to the end.
Easy, right?
Get the English Learning app — where kids learn to read the fun way!